

STEPHEN A. INGRAM

Fullstack Software Engineer



Contact



stephen.a.ingram@gmail.com



+49 (0)157 3451 3003



stephen-a-ingram.netlify.com



Gersdorfstr. 30 12105 Berlin





Profile

I am a frontend/backend developer living and working in Berlin, Germany. My early career was predominantly backend but in recent years I have been pivoting to more modern frontend languages and tooling, just because the pace of change and invention there is more exciting to me.

Date of Birth

24. October 1965

Tech Stack / Expertise

JavaScript Java React React Native PostgreSQL Node.js



Unix Docker Python Go mongoDB



Experience

2018 - NOW

Freelance Developer

Kunstmatrix Technologies GmBH, Berlin

The company develops web pages and apps, as well as providing online 3D art galleries.

- Various projects, external and internal, involved in the Health and 3D spaces, predominantly in React, with some Go(lang)
- TECH STACK:

React, Go(lang), Docker, Unix, Vue

2009 - NOW

Freelance Developer

Arcos Inc./SAMsix Inc - New York, US

ARCOS LLC is a software company based in Columbus, Ohio, that provides an automated crew callout and resource management software system for finding, assembling and tracking repair crews for electric and gas utility companies.

- Customer facing developer role for major utility clients based in the US and in Europe.
- Extending mapping software for Utility assets (cables, pipes, poles etc) and Disaster Recovery applications for storm work.

■ TECH STACK:

Java, JavaScript, Groovy, Python, PostgreSQL, UNIX scripting and administration, Oracle

(continued on page 2)



STEPHEN A. INGRAM

Fullstack Software Engineer



Tech-Radar

What I am currently learning or investigating:

- Go(lang)
- mongodb
- Node.js
- Kotlin/Native
- TypeScript
- Docker/Kubernetes
- Swift
- Flutter/Dart

Languages

English

Native speaker

German

Level A1/A2

Interests



tending a communal garden



reading

Experience

(continued)

2000 - 2009

Lead Developer

SAMsix Inc. - New York, US

■ Design of utility grade vector/raster mapping software for US/European utilities from scratch.

■ TECH STACK:

Java, PostgreSQL, JavaScript and a whole variety of other data sources (Oracle etc.) to convert bespoke utility data to a common standard.

1996 - 2000

Development Manager/Lead

ICL/Fujitsu - Washington D.C/New York, US, and Liverpool, UK

- Partner with Xerox to support 30 utility companies across the US using Xerox's bespoke mapping suite.
- Headed up development team in Washington, D.C. and the UK.
- TECH STACK:

C, Sybase, Graphics macro language

1994 - 1996

Freelance Developer

Greenpeace UK, London

- Development of a National Water Quality database to monitor water quality across all UK counties.
- TECH STACK:

MicroSoft BASIC, Access

Education

1987 - 1989

University of Liverpool

Bachelors of Science with Single Honours in Computer Science